<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ossama Ahmed</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ossama Ahmed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:27:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks Designing Neural Networks (Poster)</title>
      <link>/publication/neural/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 10:27:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/neural/</guid>
      <description>Hardware and Algorithms for Learning On-a-chip (HALO) 2016, Workshop on, Nov 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Robot Challenge</title>
      <link>/project/real_robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 23:17:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/real_robot/</guid>
      <description>Currently co-organizing a new real robotics challenge to advance the state-of-the-art in robotic manipulation, a key skill required to deploy robots in the real world. Where we host multiple robotic platforms at the Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems. Participants will submit their code as they would for a cluster, and it will then be executed automatically on our platforms. This will allow teams to gather hundreds of hours of real robot data with minimal effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal World</title>
      <link>/project/causal_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 22:56:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/causal_world/</guid>
      <description>CausalWorld is an open-source simulation framework and benchmark for causal structure and transfer learning in a robotic manipulation environment (powered by bullet) where tasks range from rather simple to extremely hard. Tasks consist of constructing 3D shapes from a given set of blocks - inspired by how children learn to build complex structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CausalWorld: A Robotics Manipulation Benchmark For Causal Structure And Transfer Learning</title>
      <link>/publication/causal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/causal/</guid>
      <description>Submitted to ICLR</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackbox MPC</title>
      <link>/project/blackbox_mpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 23:23:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/blackbox_mpc/</guid>
      <description>A framework of different derivative-free optimizers which can be used in conjunction  with a model predictive controller and a learned dynamics model to control an agent in a mujoco or a gym environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep 3D Human Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>/project/pose_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pose_estimation/</guid>
      <description>Proposed a pipeline that comprises one of the most recent approaches, namely the HighResolution Network combined with a lowweight baseline model for extracting the 3D skeleton of human subjects applied to the Human3.6M dataset; splitting the challenge to image-related and geometric-related tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Behavioral Cloning on Policy Gradient Methods</title>
      <link>/project/anymal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/anymal/</guid>
      <description>With the increasing complexity of robots and the environments they interact with, crafting manual locomotion controllers becomes a challenging task to achieve. As evident from the recent research in this field, reinforcement learning (RL) contin- ues to emerge as an attractive solution for learning locomotion policies in high- dimensional continuous domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Exploration Based on TSDF</title>
      <link>/project/plr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/plr/</guid>
      <description>Most current exploration algorithms are based on heuristics and sampling/evaluating many potential viewpoints. The goal of this work is to learn an ideal motion to maximize the known space based on a local map representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Adaptation using Graph Networks</title>
      <link>/project/meta_rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/meta_rl/</guid>
      <description>Considered learning online adaptation in a model-based reinforcement learning context where we train a dynamics model, implemented as a Graph Neural Network, in conjunction with using MPC to control a system where the controller adapts to changes in the environment or tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duckie Town</title>
      <link>/project/duckie_town/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/duckie_town/</guid>
      <description>Successfully implemented a path planner and a velocity profiler for duckiebots as part of duckietown, a robotics outreach and educational platform, while taking into account various sources of uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sparse Monocular Visual Odometry Pipeline</title>
      <link>/project/visual_odometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/visual_odometry/</guid>
      <description>Successfully implemented a monocular visual odometry (VO) pipeline with the most essential features: initialization of 3D landmarks, key point tracking between two frames, pose estimation using established 2D ↔ 3D correspondences, and triangulation of new landmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk on Expected Policy Gradients</title>
      <link>/talk/my-talk-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/my-talk-name/</guid>
      <description>Paper review of expected policy gradients &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.05374.pdf&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.05374.pdf&lt;/a&gt; by Kamil Ciosek and Shimon Whiteson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telepresence System</title>
      <link>/project/capstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/capstone/</guid>
      <description>Successfully developed a Telepresence System that is equipped with high definition cameras remotely connected to an Oculus Rift. The purpose of the Telepresence System is to allow the users to see as if they were physically in place of the system itself. The project focused on three main areas: distortion removal, panoramic frame stitching and high definition video streaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enigma Machine</title>
      <link>/project/enigma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/enigma/</guid>
      <description>Designed, built and tested a model of a digital Enigma Machine, a cipher machine used in WWII, on an FPGA board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoLite Compiler</title>
      <link>/project/go_lite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/go_lite/</guid>
      <description>Designed a compiler for GoLite, a subset of the Go programming language. Built the entire compiler pipeline (parser, syntax tree, type checker, code generator and optimizer), producing Java Byte Code as the target language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HUS AI agent</title>
      <link>/project/hus_ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/hus_ai/</guid>
      <description>Created an Artificial Intelligence agent to compete against more than 200 engineering students to play the HUS game, which is from the family of “Mancala Games”, using Reinforcement Learning Techniques. The agent ranked from the top 10%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch the Flag Robot</title>
      <link>/project/catch_the_flag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/catch_the_flag/</guid>
      <description>Led my team in developing an autonomous robot, in a team of 5 students, to compete against more than 120 engineering students to play catch the flag game, where we ranked 3/25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bomberman Game</title>
      <link>/project/bomberman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bomberman/</guid>
      <description>Implemented a modified version of this game with integrated account management system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
