<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics | Ossama Ahmed</title>
    <link>/tag/robotics/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Robotics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hub02f11719440bf94480d1ab9e24c040b_69343_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Robotics</title>
      <link>/tag/robotics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Exploration Based on TSDF</title>
      <link>/project/plr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/plr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to enable robots to explore and assist in complex unknown environments, we propose a learning-based approach for exploring unknown cluttered environments. The underlying exploration model is an end to end neural
network policy trained using reinforcement learning (RL) to use the euclidean
signed distance fields (ESDFs) local map to efficiently navigate and explore the
surrounding environment with no prior information about the environment itself.
We evaluate our approach using different RL algorithms and reward functions.
We show in simulation that the proposed exploration approach can effectively
determine appropiate frontier locations to navigate to while being robust to different environment layouts. We also show that compressing the ESDF local map to a
meaningful descriptor accelarates the training process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duckie Town</title>
      <link>/project/duckie_town/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/duckie_town/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What would a self-driving car do if the car just in front it has malfunctioning break lights? What would it do if a kid suddenly lets go of his mother’s grasp and jumps into the road? What would it do if the sensors it uses for perception break down unexpectedly? All of these situations and more may be captured if the planning algorithms are planning for such uncertainties, which include the behavior of other agents in the environment as well as our perception of the environment itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
